（干央(かんおう)）小僧 貴様の百人隊に
殿より名を授かったか？
Boy... Did your Hundred-Man Unit receive a name from my Lord?
（信(しん)）“飛信(ひしん)隊”
Feixin Unit.
ふむ…
趙(ちょう)の将軍 馮忌(ふうき)の首
飛信隊の信が 討ち取ったぞ！
The head of the Zhao General Feng Ji
has been taken by Xin of the Feixin Unit!
（壁(へき)）よくやったな 信
本当に お前というヤツは…
You did well, Xin.
You seriously are something...
何言ってんだよ　壁のあんちゃんが
敵の歩兵を止めてたから…
What're ya talking about?
I only did it because you stopped the enemy foot soldiers, Brother Bi.
Lord Xin!
（渕(えん)）信どの！
（信）オッ…
あいつら 無事だったのか
They made it out okay?!
You did it!
悪い　話は あとだ
（壁）うん？ あっ…
Sorry, we'll talk later.
そうか
I see.
すっかり隊長になったんだな 信
You've truly become a unit captain, Xin.
（王騎(おうき)）いつまでも 過ぎたことに
とらわれている場合では―
Now is not the time to be endlessly enraptured by that which has passed, Youngster Xin.
ありませんよ 童 信
（信）うん？
王騎将軍…
General Wang Qi.
（王騎）おやおや 将軍じきじきに
My, my.
Now the general is coming in person to thank you for your work today.
今日のあなたの働きを
ねぎらいに来ているんですよ
もう少し うれしそうな顔をなさい
かわいくありませんねえ
Won't you make a bit of a happier face?
That one isn't cute at all.
童 信　なぜ私が あなたの部隊に
名前を与えたか分かりますか？
Youngster Xin,
do you know why I gave a name to your unit?
覚えやすくするためです
敵にも味方にも
It was to make it easier to remember.
To enemies and to allies.
敵にも？
To enemies, too?
あなたが馮忌を討ったとき
When you killed Feng Ji,
干央は 飛信隊と あなたの名前を
高らかに明かしました
Gan Yang called out your name and the Feixin Unit for all to hear.
Feng Ji was a well-renowned general.
馮忌は名だたる武将
それを討った あなたの名は―
Having taken him down,
趙国軍のみならず
やがて 中華全土に広まるでしょう
your name will spread to not only to all of the State of Zhao, but to all of China.
俺の名前が中華全土に？
My name... all across China?
Though, just for a moment.
とはいっても 一瞬ですよ
ココココッ…
（信）一瞬…
A moment...
たとえ一瞬でも 俺の名前が…
Even if it's just for a moment, my name...
Yes... This is fine...
そうか これでいいんだ
これを繰り返せば 少しずつ
名前が中華全土に染み込んでいく
If I can repeat this,
my name will start to permeate throughout China little by little.
そうやって なるんだ
And then I will become it...
天下の大将軍に！
the greatest general under the heavens!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
時は紀元前 春秋戦国時代の秦国(しんこく)
The setting is before the common era,
in the State of Qin during the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
名もなき少年 信は
若き王 政(せい)と出会い―
The nameless boy Xin met with the young King Zheng,
武功を上げて
ついに 百人隊の将にまでなった
distinguished himself in war, and finally become a Hundred-Man General.
そんな中 突然 隣国の趙が攻め入り
未曽有の危機が訪れる
Among those events, the neighboring State of Zhao suddenly invaded,
presenting an unprecedented crisis.
総大将 王騎は
いかなる戦いを仕掛けるのか
What kind of war will Supreme Commander Wang Qi wage?
そして
信は いかなる成長を遂げるのか
And what kind of growth with Xin achieve?
Presented by Anime-Destiny
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
Translation
kewl0210
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
kewl0210
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Sudden Change in the Tide of Battle
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）戦は ２日目を迎えた
The war entered its second day.
秦軍が主力を注ぐ中央での戦い
The Qin Army concentrated its efforts on a battle in the central area...
それが焦点となる この日の主役は
With that as the focal point, the protagonist of this day is...
蒙武(もうぶ)であった
Meng Wu.
Soldiers, today will be the same as yesterday!
（蒙武）歩兵ども 昨日と同じだ！
俺の背中を追え！
Follow after me!
ほう… 盛り上がってますねえ
Oh, they really have gotten fired up...
騰(とう) 昨日の蒙武軍の被害は
いかほどですか？
Teng, what were the Meng Wu Army's losses yesterday?
（騰）
はっ！ およそ600と聞いています
Yes, sir. I heard it was approximately 600.
（王騎）600…
600...
あれほどの激戦を
繰り広げたにしては―
For such a fierce battle that it turned into, that seems like a small number, but...
少ないようですが
なるほど　そうですか
I see. Is that right?
（蒙武）全軍…
All units,
charge!
突撃ーっ！
（李白(りはく)）重歩兵 斜めに構えよ
Heavy soldiers, take slanted positions!
（貂(てん)）始まった
It started!
でも これじゃ…
But this is...
昨日と同じ …ですか？
The same as yesterday, he says?
いいえ
Well, actually...
これは
興味深いものが見られそうです
this will likely be something well worth seeing.
李白 貴様の名前は知っている
Li Bai, I know your name.
Your strength lies in your defense.
守りを得意とし
いかなる敵にも敗北したことがない
You have never lost against any of your countless enemies.
中華が認める守備の将軍
China acknowledges you as the General of Defense.
笑わせるな！
Don't make me laugh!
（趙兵たち）ウワーッ！
貴様は 相手に恵まれていただけだ
You were merely blessed with weak opponents!
（貂）昨日は あんなに防がれた
斜めの陣に 今日は一撃で入った
That tilted battle formation that blocked so much yesterday
was penetrated in one attack today!
一体 どうなってるんだ？
What in the world is going on?
（蒙毅(もうき)）ひょっとしたら
昨日も その気なら―
Perhaps...
if they had felt like it, they could've penetrated it yesterday, as well.
突入できたのかもしれない
（貂）えっ？
So they didn't break through on purpose?
じゃ わざと突入しなかった？
なんで？
Why?
（騰）歩兵たちを訓練した？
（王騎）そうです
Training his foot soldiers?
Yes.
今回の戦に
参加している秦国の歩兵は―
The foot soldiers participating in this war on the State of Qin side
急遽(きゅうきょ) 集められた者ばかりで
士気が低く
are all people assembled in a hurry, and therefore have low morale.
蒙武直属の騎馬隊との
落差が大きかった
There was a huge difference between them  and the mounted unit directly under Meng Wu.
それでは ひとつの軍として
戦えません　そこで…
Therefore they could not fight as one army. And so...
昨日は深入りを避けて味方の被害を
少なくする戦い方を選んだ
They avoided any deep involvement yesterday.
He chose a strategy where he would have fewer casualties on his side.
周りからは 李白将軍の陣形を
攻めあぐねたように見えたけど
From an onlooker's perspective, they may have looked like they were lost on how to combat General Li Bai's battle formation.
蒙武軍の歩兵たちは
どう感じただろう？
But what do you think the foot soldiers of the Meng Wu Army felt?
敵の陣地に突撃して
攻め続けているのは自分たちで―
Well, against their constant attacks to try to penetrate the enemy formation, all the enemy did was defend...
敵は じっと守ってるだけ…
そうか！
歩兵たちは自信をつけたんだ
I see! The foot soldiers gained confidence.
自信の大きさは 士気の高さ
Greater confidence is higher morale.
昨日と今日とでは 蒙武軍の
歩兵たちは 全く別の軍隊ですよ
The Meng Wu Army's foot soldiers of yesterday are now a completely different army today.
（趙兵たち）ウワーッ！
（王騎）なかなか
やるじゃないですか 蒙武さん
That Meng Wu is quite something, isn't he?
（趙荘(ちょうそう)）だが この程度で
李白の守りを破ることはできぬ
But this will is not enough to penetrate Li Bai's defense.
（趙荘）見せてやれ 李白
お前が操る陣形の恐ろしさを
Show me, Li Bai...
the ferocity of the formations you control!
“蛇”を使うぞ
（副官）はっ！
We will use "Snake"!
Yes, sir!
What?!
（貂）何だ？
李白軍の陣形が変わっていく
The Li Bai Army formation is changing!
斜めの陣の後ろが 横にズレて
蒙武が突入した地点に厚みを作った
The back of the diagonal formation is sliding sideways,
and they've concentrated it around the point Meng Wu penetrated.
And meanwhile, the front is forming a big bend,
一方 前は大きく折れ曲がり
蒙武軍の背後まで覆いかぶさった
and has even covered the Meng Wu Army's rear.
これは もはや守備の陣形じゃない
This is no longer a defensive formation!
李白軍は 蒙武軍を囲い込んで
全滅させるつもりだ
The Li Bai Army is intending to surround the Meng Wu Army and annihilate it!
（王騎）あらあら…
一気にいくかと思いきや
Oh, my... I thought they might go for it all at once.
李白さんのほうが うわてでしたね
So Li Bai was the superior one here.
完全に囲まれてしまいましたよ
Oh, they're completely surrounded now.
どうするおつもりですか？
蒙武さん
Now what will you do, Meng Wu?
All units, forward march!
全軍 このまま進め！
ンフフフッ…
面白くなってきました
Now things have gotten interesting.
（副官）李白さま あの男…
Lord Li Bai! That man...
かまわぬ　続けよ
１人の武人の力など知れている
Pay him no mind. Continue!
I know what the power of one warrior can be.
（貂）ムリだよ！
That's too much!
いくら蒙毅の親父(おやじ)さんが強くても
あんな戦い方 長くは続かない
No matter how strong your father is, Meng Yi,
he won't last long fighting that way!
蒙毅？
（蒙毅）これだ…
Meng Yi?
This is it...
かつて 先生が おっしゃっていた
Teacher told me about this a long time ago...
“強き武人を倒すために
戦略を練る”
In order to defeat powerful warriors, you need to polish your strategies.
On a battlefield where over 10,000 soldiers are fighting, strategy is everything.
“万を超す兵士が戦う戦場では
戦略が全て”
“だからこそ 全く逆のものを
見てみたいと願うこともある”と
That is why it is sometimes desirable to see the exact opposite.
僕たちは今
それを目の当たりにしているんだ
We are witnessing that right now...
武人の力が戦略を凌駕(りょうが)するところを
The power of a warrior overcoming strategy...!
ンンッ… バケモノめ
That monster... Let's retreat for the time being.
いったん ひくぞ
蒙武… 貴様が
どれだけ力を振るおうとも―
Meng Wu...
No matter how much power you wield,
この首には届かんぞ
you will never reach my neck.
Li Bai, you seem to be mistaken.
（蒙武）
李白よ 何を勘違いしている？
貴様ごときの首に興味はない
I am not interested in the head of the likes of you.
This is an order to all units,
全軍に告ぐ！
蹂躙(じゅうりん)しろー！
trample them!
将軍を失った残りの兵といえども
１万はいます
Despite being remnant soldiers that have lost their general,
there are still 10,000 of them.
それを葬ってくれれば大助かりです
ねえ？ 騰
Interring them will be a great boon. Don't you think, Teng?
Yes, sir!
はっ！ 兵の数の差を縮めたい
我が軍にとって 大きな収穫です
For our army which desires to shrink the difference in numbers,
it is a large gain.
Meng Wu...
（王騎）蒙武…
独り善がりに暴走する武人
…というウワサが広まっていますが
The rumors that he is a warrior which goes on ego-driven rampages have spread far...
実像は 大きく異なるようですね
But the truth seems to be quite different.
とはいえ―
However, it will take another battle or two for me to evaluate your strength.
あなたの力を評価するのは
もう１～２戦 様子を見てからです
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）
攻撃力が秦国イチの蒙武に―
Meng Wu, the most powerful offense in all of the State of Qin,
attacking Li Bai, the man who boasts of iron-wall defense...
鉄壁の守備を誇る李白を攻めさせる
（昌文君）理にかなっているうえに
It has a sensible and moreover playful feel to it.
遊び心すら
感じさせる王騎らしい戦い方です
Truly a Wang Qi-like style of battle.
（政）だが 戦況が
不利であることに変わりはないぞ
But... there is no change in that we are disadvantageous in the battle.
（昌文君）王騎のことです
次の手を考えておりましょう
This is Wang Qi, remember.
Let us think of the next move.
しかしながら…
But still...
（政）厳しい戦いが続くな
A harsh battle is continuing.
（貂）すごい戦いぶりだったな
蒙毅の親父さん
That was an incredible fighting style your father had, Meng Yi.
Yes.
力ずくで
相手をねじ伏せちゃったんだもんな
He brought his enemy into submission by force.
（蒙毅）そこは…
僕としては認めたくない事実だけど
That is a truth that I wouldn't like to admit, though.
ふ～ん…
あんまり喜んでないんだね…
なんで？
You don't sound too happy...
Why is that?
This is the age of strategy.
今は戦略の時代だ
武人としての力に こだわるなんて
時代に逆行している
To obsesses on the power of individual warriors would be going backwards.
（貂）でも あえて
その道を進もうとしているのが―
But your father is daring to take that path, resisting the age, isn't he?
親父さんなんだろう？
応援してやんなきゃ…
You've gotta cheer him on...
もちろん応援しているよ
Of course, I am supporting him.
僕が軍師を目指したのも―
The reason I decided to try to become a tactician
父に欠けている部分を
補いたいと思ったからだ
was to compensate for what my father lacks.
でも それは必要なかったみたいだ
But now it's looking like that wasn't necessary...
今日 見て分かった　蒙武は強いし
何ひとつ欠けてはいない
In today's battle, I saw it.
Meng Wu is strong, and he isn't lacking in a single area.
この戦は しばらく
我が父 蒙武を中心に回りそうだ
For now, it seems this war revolves around my father, Meng Wu.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）３日目
The third day.
Li Bai Army
趙軍は 蒙武軍に対抗するため
布陣を変えた
In order to combat the Meng Wu Army, the Zhao Army changed their lineup.
Gongsun Long Army
李白と公孫龍(こうそんりゅう)の両軍が共同し
Li Bai and Gongsun Long merged their two armies.
Forming a huge army of about 40,000 to attack the Meng Wu Army.
約４万の大軍で
蒙武軍を迎え撃ったのだ
しかし―
However...
それでも 蒙武は…
Regardless, Meng Wu...
could not be stopped!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）止められなかった
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
蒙武という突出した力の出現により
With the appearance of the outstanding power that was Meng Wu,
the state of battle underwent a large change.
戦局は 大きく動こうとしていた
（渉孟(しょうもう)）公孫龍 李白
Gongsun Long, Li Bai!
（渉孟）
あなたたち 何をしてるか？
What are the two of you doing?
（趙荘）２人を責めるな
Don't attack them.
これは
蒙武の力を見誤った私の失態だ
This is my error for misreading Meng Wu's power.
ならば 軍師らしく
戦略で責任を取るね 趙荘
Then be a good strategist and take responsibility with your strategy, Zhao Zhuang.
分かっている
I know. Tomorrow, we use all armies to vanquish Meng Wu.
明日 全軍で蒙武を討つぞ
（趙荘）明日も同じ布陣で 今日と
同じ戦い方をすると見せかけて―
We will give the appearance of using the same lineup tomorrow as we did today
蒙武を誘い込む
and lure Meng Wu in.
Li Bai
Gongsun Long
蒙武が攻め込んできたら―
When Meng Wu comes to attack,
Meng Wu
万極(まんごく)と渉孟で
蒙武軍を側面と背後から攻撃しろ
Wan Ji and She Meng
will attack the Meng Wu Army from the side and from behind.
She Meng
Wan Ji
（公孫龍）
その間に ほかの軍が我々の
隙を突いてきたら どう対応する？
And during that interim,
what do we do to deal with the other armies attacking our vulnerabilities?
（趙荘）考えなくていい
（どよめき）
There's no need to plan that.
ほかの軍が動く前に 蒙武を討つ！
We will kill Meng Wu before the other armies arrive!
What do you need to talk about?
（蒙武）何だ？ 話とは
そう すごまずに
まあ お座りなさい
Don't be so threatening. Please, have a seat.
要らぬ　用件を言え
Unnecessary! Tell me your business!
ンフフフッ… いいでしょう
では 用件だけ
All right, then.
We'll stick to business.
私の予想では
明日 趙軍は大きく動いてきます
My expectation is that the Zhao Army will make a big move tomorrow.
（蒙武）知ったことか
Do you think I care?
（王騎）
そう言ってくれると思ってました
I thought you would say that.
本来ならば 敵の手を考え
あれこれ対策を練るのですが
Normally, one would consider the enemy's moves and work up a plan for each situation,
今ばかりは私も あなたに賛成です
but at the moment, I agree with you.
何が言いたい？
What are you meaning to say?
今が攻め時 …ということです
That now is the time to attack.
The next morning...
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）次の朝
飛信隊は
干央が率いる第４軍に組み込まれた
the Feixin Unit joined the Fourth Army led by Gan Yang.
So you're here, Feixin Unit?!
（干央）来たか 飛信隊
貴様らの奮戦 期待しているぞ
I'm looking forward to you fighting bravely.
（兵士たち）あっ… はい！
小僧 今日も また激戦となる
覚悟しておけ
Kid, today will be another harsh battle!
Prepare yourself!
望むところだ！
You got it!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）かくして
４日目の戦が始まろうとしていた
And thus, the fourth day of battle began.
それぞれの思惑を秘め
群雄がひしめく戦場で―
With the rival generals hiding their predictions,
the one who sparks the battle on that crowded battlefield was...
口火を切ったのは…
やはり この男であった
of course, this man!
全軍 突撃ーっ！
All units...
charge!
Meng Wu... has moved...
（万極）蒙武が… 動いた
すぐ会いに行くから 待ってろよ
We'll be there soon, so wait for us.
（趙荘）まだだ　万極 渉孟
Not yet. Wan Ji, She Meng.
お前たちが動くのは 蒙武軍が
敵と味方の半ばを過ぎたとき
Your time to move will be after the Meng Wu Army has passed the mid-way point between enemies and allies.
Now!
今だ！
First Army, sortie!
（録嗚未(ろくおみ)）第１軍 出撃だ！
なに！
もうひとつの中央軍も動くだと？
What?!
Another Central Army has moved?!
2nd Army, sortie!
（隆国(りゅうこく)）第２軍 出陣！
3rd Army, let's go!
（鱗坊(りんぼう)）第３軍 出るぞ！
（同金(どうきん)）第５軍 突撃せよ！
4th Army, charge!
秦国軍のヤツらも…
The State of Qin guys are also...
山猿のぶんざいで…
Those mountain monkeys!
戦略を変えてきたか！
They changed their battle strategy?!
後れを取るな！
Don't fall behind!
第４軍 行くぞー！
（鬨の声）
4th Army, let's go!
しかも ねらいは…
And their aim is...
（王騎）趙国軍の―
the State of Zhao Army's...
本陣です ンフッ…
Headquarters!
どんなだろうな？ 尾平(びへい)
（尾平）何がだ？ 信
What do you think, Wei Ping?!
About what, Xin?
味方でさえ息が詰まる この攻撃を
受ける気分ってのはよ！
Even our allies will feel smothered...
when they try to defend this attack!
（趙荘）国境を越え
攻めているのは 我々 趙国軍で―
We should be crossing the state lines in an attack
where we, the State of Zhao Army will put you, the State of Qin Army, on the defensive.
貴様ら秦国軍は 守りに回るべき
But still... Wang Qi... You attack with all of your armies?!
それでも 王騎 貴様は
全軍で攻めに来るのか…
（貂）すごいことになったぞ…
Man, things have gotten really intense!
でも ホントに これでいいのか？
But will this really work?
If this fails, you won't be able to take it back, Wang Qi.
失敗すれば 取り返しの
つかぬことになるぞ 王騎
ンフッ… 失敗は しませんよ
It will not fail.
Right, Meng Wu?
ねえ？ 蒙武さん
（蒙武）ウオーッ！
オリャ！
（趙兵たち）ウワーッ！
楽勝だな　ここは楽勝だぞ 信
An easy victory!
This'll be an easy win for us, Xin!
Yeah!
ああ 敵は蒙武軍が おっかねえから
こっちまで気が回ってねえんだ
The enemy's afraid of the Meng Wu Army
so they won't have time to deal with us!
その隙に 敵の本陣に直行だ！
And we'll take that opportunity to head straight for the enemy headquarters!
（貂）
左から 山に侵入した軍があるぞ
The army that was in the mountains is coming from the left!
Don't tell me they're going to go straight for the State of Zhao Army headquarters?
まさか 一気に趙国軍の本陣まで
突入しちまうってのか？
本当に そう思うかい？
（貂）えっ？
Do you really think so?
No, the enemy wasn't trying to stop them from entering the mountains in the first place.
いや あの軍が山に入るのを 敵は
最初から止めようともしなかった
That means...!
…てことは！
（尾平）な… 何だよ？ これ
Wh-What is this?
（兵士たち）ウワッ！
こ… これじゃ まるで―
Th-This is... an utter...
砦(とりで)じゃねえか…
fortress, ain't it?
てめえら！ ひるむんじゃねえ！
Guys, don't falter!
ここを抜けりゃ 敵の本陣だ！
If we get through this, we'll be at the enemy's headquarters!
We don't have any path but to move forward and accept the bloodshed!
血を流して進むしか 道はねえぞ！
飛信隊 前進だ！
Feixin Unit, forward!
（趙荘）当初は 戦を重ねて
秦国軍の兵を減らしたうえで―
First, I planned to gather the armies,
and on cutting down the number of the State of Qin Army's men,
龐煖(ほうけん)さまに出ていただき
王騎の首を取るつもりだった
I was going to have Lord Pang Nuan come forward and take Wang Qi's head...
だが 蓋を開けてみれば―
But as it played out, in just four days,
たった４日で
逆に こちらが本陣に迫られる始末
we ended up being the ones with our headquarters under attack...
戦略では 王騎にも
引けを取らぬ自信があったが
In regards to strategy, I have a confidence that isn't even surpassed by Wang Qi, but...
やはり 俺では及ばぬか
it seems I fell short.
しかし…
But... it's not over!
まだだ…
まだ この戦は終わりはしない
This war is not yet over!
本陣を動かすぞ！
We're moving the troop headquarters!
Zhao Zhuang's order was conveyed to the front lines immediately.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
趙荘の命令は直ちに前線に伝わった
本陣を動かすか…
Moving the headquarters, huh?
You've made a bold move quite quickly, Zhao Zhuang!
早めに踏み切ったね 趙荘
だが この戦況では…
But with the battle in this state...
It is a wise decision.
懸命な決断であろう
Until I can commence my next strategy...
次の戦略を仕掛けるまで これ以上
兵を減らすわけには いかぬ
I cannot lose any more soldiers...
この戦
どんなことをしても勝ちにいくぞ
No matter what happens in this battle, we must reach victory.
な… なに！
What?!
どういうことだ？
What's going on?
（信）趙のヤツらが ひいていく…
The Zhao guys...
are retreating?
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）戦の様相は
更なる急展開を見せようとしていた
The state of battle has shown yet another rapid change!
（李牧）オオッ… おっと…
（カイネ）馬で
迂回(うかい)したほうが よかったのでは？
Would you rather we'd gone around on horseback?
いえ
こちらのほうが早いと聞きました
No, I heard this way would be faster.
ほら！ オッ… やってる やってる
間に合いましたよ
Look!
Yes, all right!
We've made it in time!
ご覧なさい カイネ
（カイネ）見てますよ
Take a look, Kaine.
I'm looking.
（李牧）さあ 皆さん
Now, everyone!
李牧が到着しましたよ
Li Mu has arrived!
michi wa tsuzuku yume wo oimotome
路は続く　夢を追い求め
The path goes on, chasing after a dream.
nozomu saki ni kimi no ashita wa aru no?
望む先に　君の明日はあるの？
Will your tomorrow be at the place my hopes lead?
kizutsuite kokoro mo mada kawaku nara
傷ついて　心もまだ渇くなら
If I get hurt and my heart is still thirsty,
koko e kite nando demo utau kara
ここへ来て何度でも歌うから
I'll come here and sing as many times as it takes.
owari naki tatakai no naka de
終わりなき戦いの中で
In this endless battle
kimi wa tsuyoku kawaru
君は強く変わる
You change to become stronger.
kono sora wo kirisaita ikazuchi wa kimi
この空を切り裂いた　雷は君
The lightning that cut apart this sky is you.
osore wo koete tachimukau hikari no ya hashiridasu
恐れを超えて立ち向かう　光の矢　走りだす
The arrow of light that overcomes fear faces forward and shoots forth.
tsukamu sadame shinjitsuzukeru no...
掴む　運命　信じ続けるの…
I'll grab onto the destiny I've always believed in...
～♪
Preview
I need to go help them...
（渕）助けに行かねば… 助けに…
Help them...
みんなが死んでいく…
Everyone is dying!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）これは悪夢か？
Is this a nightmare?
一方的な破壊を前に
逃れるすべはない
Before unilateral destruction,
Disaster
there is no means of escape!
End
Disaster
次回 “天災”
Next time,